officialroyalwedding2011.org 2012-11-21

# The Royal Wedding

**Privacy Policy**

Our policy is to respect and protect the privacy of anyone who visits www.officialroyalwedding2011.org (the site). Clarence House uses all reasonable endeavours to comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA). 

This policy, together with our Terms and Conditions of Use, and any other documents referred to in them, sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

 **Who is the Data Controller?**

For the purposes of the DPA, the data controller is the Principal Private Secretary for the Household of TRH The Prince of Wales and The Duchess of Cornwall. Correspondence may be addressed to Clarence House, London, SW1A 1BA, marked for the attention of the Correspondence Department.

 **Information we collect from you**

•    Information that you provide by filling in forms on the site. This includes information provided at the time of subscribing for any services provided by us through the site (including updates). we may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by third parties (including companies) connected with The Prince of Wales and when you report a problem with the site.   
•    If you contact us (by post, email or any other method), we may keep a record of that correspondence.   
•    We (or our agents) may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.   
•    Details of your visits to the site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data and the resources that you access. 

**IP Addresses and Cookies**

During your use of the site we may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser types, for system administration and to report aggregate information to third parties (including organisations connected with Members of the Royal Family). This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general Internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve the site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. For more information about cookies, please visit www.allaboutcookies.org. You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to the site.

We do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that while your user session will be logged, you will remain anonymous to us.  Web Analytics tool Google Analytics is  used on the site to gather statistical information about site usage.  It identifies website trends without identifying individual visitors.  Read more at [http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html ](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html "http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html")**Use made of the information**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

•    to enable us to tailor the site to your particular interests;   
•    to ensure that the content from the site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;   
•    to provide you with information that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;   
•    to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;   
•    to notify you about changes to our service. 

We may also monitor user traffic on an aggregate basis in order to help us develop and improve the site for the benefit of all users. This data does not contain personal information. Please note in particular that statistical records are maintained of pages visited by users whether or not they have subscribed for any of our services.

All personal data will be held in a secure manner and will not be used for marketing purposes or used for any purpose not stated in this Privacy Policy or the Terms and Conditions of Use without your permission. We will however send personally identifiable information about you to other organisations, companies or people when:

•    we have your consent to share the information;   
•    we respond to court orders or other legal processes;   
•    we are required by law to provide information to others or we (in good faith) believe that we are required to do so by any order of the Courts or other competent body or agency;   
•    we are required to do so for the protection or defence of rights or property or to protect the personal safety of Clarence House employees or the public at large; and   
•    a service you have requested is supplied by a partner organisation on our behalf.   
We will not otherwise sell or pass your personal data on to any third parties without first obtaining your consent.  
 **  
Security**

You are advised that the Internet is not a secure medium. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that data transmitted electronically to the site or otherwise and stored by us is not accessed by unauthorised third parties in accordance with the requirements of the DPA. However, you accept the risk that data transmitted electronically to the site or otherwise may be intercepted before reaching the site or accessed from our data storage by third parties not authorised by us and may be exploited unlawfully by such unauthorised third parties. 

Once we have received your information, we will use reasonable endeavours to keep your information confidential and store it on a secure server which is password protected and hidden behind a firewall from the outside world. Internal procedures cover the storage access and disclosures of your information.   
**  
Children**

We may ask children to submit material to us for posting up on the site.  Our policy is not to collect or publish any personal information relating to any child under 13 unless the child's parent or guardian has first written to us with that parent's or guardian's consent. We collect and publish only limited personal information from children (like their first name, age and general location). We may collect a child's email address in order to receive material from the child by email, but we promptly delete the email address from our system.  We urge parents to regularly monitor and supervise their children’s on-line activities.

 **Links**

The site has links to other websites which will have different privacy, trading and use policies and conditions and you should familiarise yourself with these policies before you use or submit any personal data to these websites.

 **Google Search Engine**

The search box on this website (“Search Box”) is powered by Google inc (“Google”). Customer acknowledges and agrees that Google’s privacy policy (located at <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy.  
 **  
Changes to our Privacy Policy**

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page.

 **Contact Us**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to: The Correspondence Department, Clarence House, London, SW1A 1BA.

For more information on the Data Protection Act, visit [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/ "www.ico.gov.uk") or call (UK) 01625 545745.
